m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：阿蘅阿蘅  猫中之王  醉芝士
校对：终极挑战YY猫  接受挑战赛太公  总监   YY猫
后期：孤帆     时间轴：加森
老爸老妈浪漫史
第九季  第九集
周六早上11点
真不敢相信你妈居然不来参加婚礼
I can't believe Your mom's not coming to the wedding?
距婚礼还有31个小时
说真的  我不想再哭了
Okay, seriously, I-I need to stop crying.
你们知道怎么止住眼泪吗
Does anyone know how to turn this off?
是不是有个开关什么的
Is there, like, a button or something?
要我帮你找找吗
Want me to feel around for it?
可能在你的背上
It's probably somewhere on your back.
-住手  -怎么了  我只是想让你高兴点
- Stop it. - What? I'm trying to cheer you up.
我觉得现阶段这是不可能的
I don't think that's possible at this point.
接受挑战
Challenge accepted!
别闹了  巴尼
No, Barney,
我只是不想再哭了  仅此而已
I just need to get myself to stop crying, that's all.
鬼来了
Boogity-boo!
莉莉 你干嘛啊  她又不是打嗝
Lily, what the hell?! It's not the hiccups.
我只是凭直觉做事
I was just going on a hunch.
现在我开始打嗝了
And now I have the hiccups.
各位  真的不用担心我  好吗
Look, guys, just, seriously, don't worry about me, okay?
请让我用自己的方式解决
Just let me deal with this on my own.
恕我做不到  罗宾
I'm afraid that's not possible, Robin.
只要我接受了挑战  就绝不会反悔
Once I've accepted a challenge, it cannot be unaccepted.
挑战不成功  决不罢休
I will not rest until the job is done.
是吗
Oh, is that so?
那我们的尿布和咖喱角在哪
Then where are our diapers and samosas?
尿布和咖喱角  这件事发生在六个月前
Diapers and samosas. Oh, that's the story
也就是2012年的秋天
that took place six months earlier in the fall of 2012.
少校想要一杯鸡尾酒
Major craving for a mojito.
天啊
Oh, god,
你们又在玩白痴的内部[二等兵]玩笑吗
we're back to your stupid little private joke again?
七年过去了  你们居然还在玩这个
Are you guys really still doing this seven years later?
真烦人  不许玩了
It's so annoying. Just stop it.
二等兵玩笑
Private joke again?
七年过去了  你们居然还在玩这个
Are you guys really still doing this seven years later?
真烦人  不许玩了
It's so annoying. Just stop it.
谁会向二等兵敬礼啊
You don't salute a private!
-我去去就回  -好
- I'll be right back. - All right.
莉莉  你在偷蹭小腿勾搭我吗
Lily, are you playing footsie with me?
什么  不是不是
What? Oh, no, no.
我只是试探下你的小腿在哪里
I was just feeling around for your shin.
我的小腿  为什么你要...
My shin? Why would you...?
你干嘛踢我
Ow! Why'd you do that?
提醒你痛是什么感觉
To remind you what pain is.
你和罗宾再保持这种暧昧的亲密关系
You keep it up with all the cutesy-tootsy stuff with Robin,
小心生出更多的事端
gonna be a whole lot more where that came from.
莉莉  你不用担心
Lily, you have nothing to worry about.
我才不会  你和罗宾是纯友谊
I better not. You and Robin are platonic.
拜托  泰德和罗宾才不是纯友谊
Please. Ted and Robin are not platonic.
就像我和罗宾不是纯友谊那样
Just like me and Robin are not platonic.
世界上两个单身的人永远不可能
Just like no two single people in the world
保持纯友谊关系
are ever platonic.
观点就是  如果在二十分钟内
Symposium: two people are only platonic
两个人都没有勾搭对方的苗头
if in the next 20 minutes there is no
那就是纯友谊关系
chance of them hooking up.
老实说  我只认识两个人能保持纯友谊关系
Truth is, I only know of one genuinely platonic relationship.
你和我
You and me.
别开玩笑了  莉莉
Don't make me laugh, Lily.
你超级想勾搭我的好吗
You want to hit this so hard.
说真的  她正偷蹭我腿呢
Seriously, she's playing footsies with me as I... Ow!
我说的是马修和罗宾
No, I'm talking about Marshall and Robin.
即使如下情况发生  马修和罗宾绝不会搞上
Marshall and Robin wouldn't hook up even if this happened:
马修  罗宾
Marshall, Robin!
如果你们俩二十分钟内不火力全开亲热的话
If you guys don't full-on make out in the next 20 minutes,
他们就会炸了我和酒吧里的所有人
they're gonna blow me up and everyone in this bar!
天啊  除了罗宾谁都行
My God, no! Anyone but Robin.
我真的不想这么做
I really don't want to do this!
我们没时间了  快点
Guys, we have no time! Just do it!
十九分钟后
对不起  宝贝  我做不到
I'm sorry, baby, I just, I can't do it.
我是唯一的幸存者
And the only survivor was me
因为我正在楼上  和泰德的妈妈上床
because I was upstairs banging Ted's mom.
什么  去要金发女郎的电话吗
What? Get that blond girl's phone number?
接受挑战
Challenge accepted.
未知来电者  别打了
Unknown caller, stop calling me.
你要接吗
Are you gonna answer it?
你以为现在是1994年
Yeah, 'cause it's 1994
即使不知道来电者是谁
and I'm gonna pick up a phone
我也会接电话吗
without knowing who's on the other end.
-我该走了  -泰德
- I should get going. - Ted...
莉莉  根据"纯友谊"这个词的所有解释
Lily, by every definition of the word platonic,
包括巴尼那个假解释
including Barney's fake one,
我可以百分百确定
I can say with total certainty...
甘蓝菜
that Brussels sprouts
是21世纪再度走红的蔬菜
are the comeback vegetable of the 21st century.
-回见  -再见
- Well, see you guys later. - Bye.
挑战成功
Challenge completed.
抱歉  我错过了前半部分
I'm sorry. I-I missed the first half of this.
一个喝醉的妞  独坐在那里
Um, why is picking up a drunk chick sitting alone
手指抚摸着婚戒留下的痕迹
and rubbing a tan line on her finger
你泡到她是应该的  怎么能称为挑战呢
where a wedding ring used to be, a challenge?
因为我说接受挑战啊
Because I said challenge accepted.
看  这就是你的问题了  巴尼
See? That's your problem, Barney.
你只接受你想出来的挑战
You only accept challenges you came up with.
你什么时候也接受
Just once, I'd like to see you accept
别人提出的挑战
someone else's challenge.
挑战接...  等等  什么挑战
Challenge acc... Wait-- What's the challenge?
有意思
Interesting.
一个充满无限可能的机会
An opportunity rife with possibilities.
我们得来点有想象力的挑战
We need to find something with just the right amount of poetic...
学海豚说话  去要女孩子的电话
Get a girl's number while talking like a dolphin!
那也行
That works.
接受挑战
哈林花式篮球
睁大眼睛看清楚  裁判  那不是怀孕的女人
Open your eyes, ref! That's not a pregnant lady!
他衣服里面藏着一颗篮球
It's a basketball under his shirt!
快吹哨子啊
Blow the freakin' whistle!
巴尼说得对
Anyways, Barney's right;
我肯定情愿让酒吧被炸掉
I would absolutely let the bar blow up.
但是你会死  莉莉也会死
But you'd die, and Lily would die, too.
没错  但能让我们的魂魄留在酒吧里吓人
Yeah, but then we could haunt the bar for eternity
这正中我们下怀
like we always planned.
总之  罗宾是你的女人
Anyways, Robin's your girl.
我们怎么老是回到这个话题[这里]呢
Why do we keep coming back to this?
比赛有趣  票也便宜  还能离家出来透透气
It's fun. Tickets are cheap. Gets us out of the house.
我是说我和罗宾
No, me and Robin.
因为罗宾告诉我  她还爱着你
Because Robin told me that she's still in love with you.
你说真的吗
Are you seriou?
罗宾告诉你  她还爱我吗
Robin told you that she's still in love with me?
没说  是我编的
No, I just made that up.
不过这假话说值了  因为你的表情
But it was worth it because I can tell
告诉我你还对罗宾还有感觉
by that look on your face that you still have feelings for Robin.
球放在篮筐上了
Okay, ball is sitting on the basket!
虽然没有犯规  但是不安全
That's not only illegal, it's unsafe!
拜托  金斯  防御啊
Come on, Gens, D up!
康乃迪克州的森里里有一家修道院
It's this monastery in Connecticut out in the woods,
那里的修女能做出美味的奶酪
and the nuns there, they make this gourmet cheese.
超级好吃的
It's just amazing.
这已经是第三杯酒了吗
Wow, was that three glasses of wine?
时间过得真快
Where does the time go.
我知道你要回去做研究了
Look, I know that you need to get back to your studies.
要不我们改天再约吧
Maybe we could get together some other time?
不  不可能吧
No! Not possible!
那是我一生中最精彩的表演
It was the performance of a lifetime.
如果我和她再多待一会
Man, if I'd have hung around for a few more minutes,
我可能已经让她
I probably could have gotten her
-摸我的"喷水孔"了  -手机给我
- to touch my blowhole. - Give me that.
喂
Hello?
你刚刚把你的电话给了一个
Hi, did you just give your phone number to a guy
像海豚一样叽叽叫的男人吗
who was squeaking like a dolphin?
是的
Yeah.
亲爱的  听我一句
Honey, listen to me.
我要你这一年  这一整年
I need you to take a year, a full year
都保持独身  知道吗
and just be celibate, okay?
不要接触男人
No boys.
一年
One year.
你知道我是对的
I think you know I'm right about this.
-你是对的  -没错
- You're right. - Yeah.
真是让人心酸
That was heartbreaking.
裤子也栓不住
And pants-breaking Boing-oing-oing!
好了  下一个挑战
All right, next challenge.
今晚都要玩这个吗
Oh, this is an all-night thing?
好吧  穿着垃圾袋
Okay, um, pick up a girl...
去泡个妞
wearing a garbage bag.
非常"乐意"
I'd be "Glad" To.
"乐意"'和"巨大"两者皆为垃圾袋制造商
希望她别太"巨大"
Just hope she's not too "Hefty."
我只能想到这两个垃圾袋品牌
And those are all of the brands of trash bags I can think of.
我还没说完
I'm not done.
你也不能说带"E"的字
You also can't use the letter "E."
"几"受挑战
Challng... accptd-d.
你是单身  她也是单身
You're single, she's single.
是时候在一起了
It's time to do this.
你之所以这么说  是因为你和莉莉打赌
You're only saying this because you bet Lily
我和罗宾最后会在一起
that Robin and I would end up together,
你想赢那五块钱
and you want that five bucks.
我想要那五块钱  泰德
I need that five bucks, Ted.
但是更重要的是  我想要你开心
But more importantly, I need you to be happy.
马修  我们之间是纯友谊
Marshall, we're platonic.
可你们之间才不是纯友谊
But you're not platonic!
你离你的幸福生活只有短短二十分钟的时间
You are 20 short minutes away from happily ever after.
当然  如果你现在就出发的话
I mean, if you left right now.
从我们相遇的那一刻  我就爱上了你
I have loved you from the moment we met.
命中注定我们要在一起
I know we're meant to be together.
我每分每秒都想跟你在一起
I don't want to waste another second without you.
我们重新开始好不好
Let's give it another shot.
好呀
Okay!
不会吧
No!
你输了  宝贝  付钱吧
Pay up, baby. Pay up.
太好了
Oh, yes!
乖乖的五块钱   快到我的碗里来 *
* Sweet, sweet five bucks, you soon will be mine
虽然我和莉莉的钱都共享 *
* Even though Lily and I share bank accounts
你还是属于我的 *
* You're already mine to begin with.
抱歉
Sorry.
而你和罗宾从此也会
And you and Robin get a lifetime of happiness,
幸福快乐一辈子
so there's that.
但你最好赶快行动
But you better hurry up
免得别人把她抢走了
before some other guy snatches her up.
是吗  谁是我的竞争对手呢
Really? And who's my competition?
好  不能用到字母E  不能用到字母E
Okay, don't use the letter "E." Don't use the letter "E."
嗨[hEy]  糟糕
Hey. Damn it.
你好  我...叫...巴尼[barnEy]
Hi. I... am...Barney.
讨厌  我名字里就有个E
Damn it! There's an E in my name!
你好  我叫
Hi. My word for...
我自己巴...诺
this guy is Barno.
巴诺  你长得
Barno. You look...
不丑
not ugly.
你的...  号码
Your... dial thing...
是多少
is what?
你想和我一起回我家吗
Do you want to just go back to my place?
好啊[yEs]  又错了
Yes. Damn it!
我想请你喝一杯
I want to buy you a drink.
不过  我该怎么称呼你
But first, what do I call you?
E莲・艾E斯坦
Elaine Edelstein.
我还是干脆明天
How about I just call you...
打给你吧
tomorrow?
小姐  你的号码是
Your digits, m'lady?
说真的  两位
Seriously, guys,
出点更有难度的题好吗
you're gonna have to try harder than that.
接受挑战
Challenge accepted.
你好
Excuse me, hi.
我是瑞恩・高斯林的个人助理
I'm Ryan Gosling's personal assistant.
他刚才看见你走进这酒吧
He saw you as you were walking in,
于是他派我过来  请你在这里等他
and he sent me over to tell you to wait here.
别激动  这可是真事哦
Be cool. This is real, okay?
不过呢  瑞恩这人特别害羞
But listen, Ryan is super shy.
我知道
I know.
如果他进来时看到
Which means that if he comes in here
你在和其他男人说话
and he sees you talking to some other guy,
他肯定转头就走
he's gonna turn right around and leave.
明白的话就点点头
Nod if you understand.
吧台的红发妞
Redhead at the bar.
接受挑战
Challenge accepted.
-你好  -滚开
- Hey, there. - Get away from me!
你是不是在尽力输球啊  艾迪
It's like you're trying to lose, Eddie!
艾迪  我上次看见
Hey, Eddie, last time I saw
这么多失误[小馅饼]还是在面包店呢
this many turnovers was at a bakery.
-你到底要不要行动  -不要
- So are you doing this or what? - No.
而且  就算我要这么做
And for the record, if I were gonna do it,
我也不会对她说"我们应该重新来过"
I wouldn't just be, like, "Hey, we should get back together."
这也太外行了吧
Amateur hour.
哥教你该怎么做
Here's how you do it.
借过  不好意思
Excuse me. Okay, sorry.
抱歉
Sorry.
现在去屋顶
别走  有小偷
Stop, thief!
那只蓝色法国号  真是太浪漫了
The blue French horn, it's so romantic!
我的天  你知道你是谁吗
Oh, my God, do you know who you are?!
擅长写浪漫爱情故事的小说家  著有《恋恋笔记本》等
你是尼可拉斯・史派克
You're Nicholas Sparks!
各位  有位名人在此
Hey, everybody, we got a, uh, celebrity
让我们欢迎  尼古拉斯・史派克
in the crowd over here. We got, uh, Nicholas Sparks!
等我说完好不好
You didn't let me finish.
泰德  听我说
Ted, listen...
我不想再经历一次这种事了
I can do without reliving that.
你是瞎眼了吗
Are you completely blind?
什么
What?
你睁眼看看好吗  裁判
Open your eyes, ref!
那球已经整整7分钟没落地了
The ball hasn't touched the ground in seven minutes!
裁判  检查一下你的语音信箱
Hey, ref, check your voicemail!
你错过了不少电话[犯规]呢
I think you've missed a few calls!
你是瞎眼了吗
Are you completely blind?!
你是说我还是
Wait-- me or...?
当然是你  泰德
You, Ted!
罗宾的想法已经改变了
Robin has changed her mind.
才怪  罗宾根本没改变
No, Robin doesn't change her mind.
她真的变了
Except that she does.
记得她以前有多讨厌
Remember how she used to claim
白人放克乐团吗
to hate white guy funk bands?
结果在我乐团
And yet, at the farewell performance of my band,
"放克  放克  一直放到死"的告别演出上
"The Funk, the Whole Funk and Nothing but the Funk,"
罗宾随着音乐点头呢
there's Robin rhythmically nodding her head
还大声要求我们唱"放弃放克"这首歌
and shouting out a request for "Give Up the Funk."
我想她当时点头  是因为我问她
I think she was nodding her head in response to my question,
"你想现在回家吗"
"Do you want to leave soon?"
而且她是认真地
And she was legitimately suggesting
叫你们别再玩放克了
that you give up the funk.
别说这事了  我已经向前看了
Can we just drop this? I have moved on.
你根本没有
Well, except that you haven't.
你不会突然想到蓝色法国号的点子
You didn't just come up with this blue French horn thing.
你之前肯定有考虑过这招
You've thought about this.
史派克先生
Mr. Sparks?
我好喜欢你的《恋恋笔记本》
I loved The Notebook.
艾迪  你都落后八十分了
Eddie, you're down by 80.
你认真比赛好不好
Will you watch the game?
别再靠近我
Do not come any closer!
不然我一定灭了你
I swear to God I will kill you.
好  我保证不靠近了
It's cool. I'm not gonna come any closer.
你一直在看门那边  你是在等人
You're looking at the door, you're waiting for someone.
某个重要的人
Someone important,
某个能填补你生活空虚的人
someone who will fill an empty space in your life.
电影明星
A movie star?
是哪一个呢
But which one?
克鲁尼  李奥纳多  泽布卡[巴尼最爱的空手道小子]
Clooney, DiCaprio, Zabka...?
都不是
No...
我猜是瑞恩
I'm gonna go with Ryan...
雷诺
Reyn...
菲利普
Phil-Phillip...
西克[美偶主持]  高斯林
Seacr... Gosling...
瑞恩・高斯林
Ryan Gosling!
没错  我等的就是瑞恩・高斯林
Yes, I'm waiting for Ryan Gosling, okay?
别再烦我了
Now, leave me alone.
姑娘  你通过了我的考验
You passed my test, girl.
-瑞恩  -不可能
- Ryan? - No.
这绝对...不可能
Just... no.
我告诉她我是演技派
I told her I'm a method actor.
我做了整容手术
And I had to get plastic surgery
为了在下一部戏里
for an upcoming role where I play a man
扮演一个比瑞恩本人还帅的角色
much more handsome than myself.
恭喜你  你赢了
Congratulations, you win.
赢了  不  我才不在乎赢呢
Win? No, I don't want to win.
我还想继续玩呢  再来几个挑战吧
I want to keep playing. More challenges.
好吧  你想要挑战吗
Fine, you want another challenge?
再来一个  再来一个
More challenges, more challenges.
好  你的挑战就是
Fine, here's your challenge.
去药店买点尿布回来
Go down to the pharmacy and buy some diapers.
再去印度馆子帮我买个印度咖喱角
And, uh, get me a Samosa from the Indian place.
这只是叫我跑腿办事吧
Sounds like an errand.
同时钓个妹子回来
While picking up a girl.
接受挑战
Challenge accepted!
拜托
Come on!
从前那个不管结局如何
Whatever happened to the guy who wasn't afraid to charge
勇于行动的人哪去了
headlong into the unknown?
结局显而易见
What unknown?
没错  八年前
Sure, eight years ago
当我偷那只蓝色法国号时
when I stole that blue French horn, yeah.
结局还是未知数
That was the unknown.
可现在  同样的事已经发生过好几次
But now? I mean, how many times have we been here?
我很清楚结局是什么
I know exactly what's gonna happen.
你知道还有谁最清楚结局吗
You know who else knew exactly what was gonna happen, Ted?
1971年1月5日的华盛顿将军队
The Washington Generals on January 5, 1971.
他们知道自己会输
They knew they were gonna lose,
却还是上场比赛
but they went in there anyway,
打出他们最好的表现
and then gave it their best shot.
最后取得了胜利  泰德
And they won that game, Ted!
这就是他们唯一获胜的原因
For one reason and for one reason only.
因为计分出错  还是敌方的卡里・尼尔还身患感冒
A scoring error and the fact that Curly Neal had the flu?
是毅力
Perseverance.
那是将军队历史上唯一一场胜利
It was the only win in Generals history,
但一场足以代表一切
but that's all you need.
只要赢一次就好
Just one win.
我去买点啤酒
I'm gonna go grab us some beers.
我不知道你是谁  也不管你想推销什么
Hi, I don't know who this is or what you're trying to sell,
可你打扰到我看哈林篮球赛了
but you are disturbing me during the Globetrotters.
泰德  我是哈蒙德・德鲁瑟
Hello, Ted, it's Hammond Druthers.
目标确定
Target acquired.
我正在为
I‘m recruiting volunteers
我工作的狗狗孤儿院招募志愿者
for the starving puppy orphanage where I work.
我是免费帮忙的
For free.
你可以留下你的电话号码吗
So, if you wouldn't mind just writing your number down
就写在报名表上
on this signup sheet...?
我很感谢你想要
Listen, I appreciate that you feel
我的电话号码
like you need my number.
也许是因为你为了某事伤心
Maybe it's because you're really sad about something
而这是你减轻痛苦的办法
and this is your way of feeling better about yourself.
但是
But...
因为我有男友  而且我相当肯定
since I have a boyfriend, and I'm pretty sure
你之前在那边管我叫"目标"
I heard you call me a target earlier over there,
-什么  -我会走开
- Wha...? - I'm gonna go ahead
不会给你我的号码
and not give you my number.
我要给你一些更棒的东西
I'm gonna give you something even better.
直奔主题了啊
Wow, right to the chase.
我去六号货道等你
Meet you in aisle six.
-我要给你这个  -好的
- I'm gonna give you this. - Okay.
一切都会好起来的
It's gonna be okay.
你是个好人
You're a good guy.
你一定会熬过这段伤心日子
You will get through this.
好吧
Uh, okay.
有怪人出没
Weirdo alert.
你见过...
Have you met...?
不好意思
Excuse me.
你说"伤心"是什么意思
What do you mean "sad"?
泰德
Ted?
我是从伊利诺伊州芝加哥打给你的
I'm calling you from Chicago, Illinois
我在一家非常成功的
where I'm a key player
建筑公司里担任重要职位
in a very successful architectural firm.
对  我听说过
Oh, yeah, I read about that.
好啦  你听说的事
All right, about what you read...
你建了座凹面的大玻璃楼
You built that big concave glass tower.
那玻璃楼把对面街的几栋楼给熔了
And it melted a few buildings across the street.
好吧  但是拜托
Yes, fine, but come on.
有哪位建筑师曾经在设计上
What architect has made a major design flaw
出现重大失误  将市水族馆的温度升至
that raised the temperature of the city aquarium
88摄氏度
to 190 degrees
干掉了数千条非常稀有的鱼
and killed thousands of very rare fish?
那已经是历史了  泰德  我已经向前看了
That's the past, Ted. I'm looking forward.
我要你加入我的团队
I want you on my team.
我不接受"不"这个答案
And I won't take no for an answer.
-不  -我想你没听清楚我的话  泰德
- No. - I don't think you heard me, Ted.
-不  -别这样  泰德
- No. - Come on, Ted!
求你了
Please?
如果你同意  公司会给我停车位
They're gonna give me a parking spot if you say yes.
-我有停车位吗  -我们可以挤一挤
- Do I get a parking spot? - Well, we can go tandem.
-不  -隔周换着用呢
- No. - Every other week then?
-不  -其实芝加哥非常适合步行
- No. - You know, Chicago's more of a walking town.
-不  -算你狠
- No. - All right!
停车位归你了
You can have the parking spot.
你这是同意了吗
So, that's a yes?
-不  -听着  泰德
- Mm, no. - Look, Ted.
我能让你的日子非常不好过
I can make your life very difficult.
-怎么做  -怎么做
- How? - How?!
我会疯狂地给你打电话
I will call you a lot.
我会疯狂地给你转推特
I will Tweet at you like crazy.
我会死占着你的脸书墙不下来
I will live on your Facebook wall!
我们不是脸书好友
We're not Facebook friends.
对啊  这是怎么回事
Yeah, what's going on with that?
我都已经申请了八个月了
It's been pending, like, for eight months now.
泰德  你现在
Look, Ted, you're a...
炙手可热
a very hot commodity.
大家都爱死巨人国家银行大楼了
Everybody loves the GNB Tower.
它没有弄瞎任何想降落在
And how it hasn't blinded any pilots
芝加哥奥黑尔机场的飞行员
on final approach into O'Hare.
而且我貌似
And I-I may have told
告诉了这里的合伙人  咱俩是死党
the partners here that you and I are very, very good friends.
求你了  说你会考虑一下  好吗
So, please, just say that you'll think about it.
好的
Fine.
我会考虑一下
I'll think about it.
德鲁瑟投篮  得分
Druthers shoots, he scores!
伤心  女士  过去一小时我拿到了14个女生的号码
Sad? Lady, I got 14 girls' numbers in the last hour.
这还只是玩票性质的一晚
And this was an off night.
我怎么可能会有伤心事
What can I possibly be sad about?
我觉得你之前碰到了真爱  却搞砸了
I think you were in love and you messed it up.
自那以后  你人生的每一刻
And every moment of your life since then
就是拼命让自己忙碌  好忽略这个事实
has been spent trying to stay busy enough to ignore that fact.
这就是巴尼和你们母亲相识的经过
And that's how Barney met your mother.
将军队队输了
Well, the Generals lost.
第四节时  比分咬得好紧
What a nail biter-- the whole fourth quarter
我的心都快跳出来了
my heart was in my throat.
最后比分呢
What was the final?
216比12
216 to 12.
现在谁都别理我  我没办法...
Nobody talk to me right now, I can't even...
比赛时发生了一件非常奇怪的事
The strangest thing happened at the game.
有个未知号码打给我
I got a phone call from an unknown number.
我接了电话
And when I answered I...
你在吃橄榄
You're eating olives.
是的
Yup.
你要这个吗
Do you want these?
我讨厌橄榄
I hate olives.
你不是讨厌橄榄吗
I... thought you hate olives.
我想我改变想法了
I guess I changed my mind.
你好  合伙人
Hello, partner!
这话听起来真带劲  对吗
Boy, that just sounds right, doesn't it?
德鲁瑟先生  其实呢
Yeah, actually, Mr. Druthers.
我的答案还是"不"
My answer is no.
什么  不  泰德  别这样
What? No, Ted, come on!
对不起  我在纽约还有事要做
I'm sorry, I still have things to do here in New York.
我要建一栋玻璃大楼
I am going to build a tower of glass
把你给熔了
and melt you with it!
-你不会的  -我不会  但你听好了
- No, you won't. - No, I won't, but know this.
过完今天
After today
这个职位你就永远别想了
this offer is gone forever.
我挂了电话后  咱们老死不相往来
When I hang up this phone, you and I are done.
-这扇门关上了  -好的
- The door is closed! - Okay.
这扇门永远对你敞开  泰德
The door's always open, Ted.
如果你改变主意了  记得打给我
If you change your mind, just call me back, okay?
再见
Bye.
我想他会来的
I think he's coming around.
我们过去谈过恋爱
We tried dating a while back
那真是一场灾难
and it was a disaster.
但我一直后悔放弃了
But I-I always regret giving up.
结束得太快了
It just ended so quickly.
你呢
What about you?
你和男友会白头偕老吗
You and your boyfriend gonna go the distance?
不知道
I don't know.
我觉得自己也许还没有碰上真命天子
I think maybe I still haven't met the right guy.
我想想有没有认识的人可以介绍给你
I wonder if I know someone to set you up with.
一片空白
Drawing a blank.
你要追回这个女生吗
Are you gonna go get this girl?
还是怎样
Or what?
我不知道
I don't know.
我现在在人生巅峰
I'm kind of at my peak right now.
我不知道能否潇洒地从游戏人生中抽身而去
I don't know if I can just walk away from the game.
你是想一直玩  还是想要赢
Do you want to keep playing or do you want to win?
我想赢
I want to win.
我在做什么呢
What am I doing?
我现在去找罗宾不用20分钟  我们以后就会...
In less than 20 minutes, Robin and I could be...
不  不行  不行
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
二十分钟可远远不够
It's gonna take a lot more than 20 minutes.
你需要付出你的一切
This is gonna take everything you have got.
你需要付出所有的时间  所有的心力
This is gonna take all of your time, all of your attention.
动用一切可利用的资源
All of your resources.
这是事关一生的一局
This is the big one.
尿布男
Diaper man.
The Magnetic Fields - 《It's Only Time》
要做就得做对
You got to do it right.
不能到处瞎玩
Can't be messing around,
在药店里泡妞
picking up girls in drug stores.
你要努力了
You got work to do.
我们不是纯友谊
We're not platonic.
也许算是"类似纯友谊"吧
Platon-ish, maybe.
不知道这算不算一个词
If that's even a word.
但肯定不是纯友谊
But not platonic.
《泡妞秘笈》
我们之间有种情愫
I mean, there's something between us.
永远都会有
And there always will be.
如果是八年前
If this was eight years ago,
我现在早就跳上计程车
I'd be jumping into a cab right now
去偷那个蓝色法国圆号了
to go steal that blue French horn.
你为什么没这样做呢
Well, why don't you?
我不知道
I don't know.
似乎现在的我不再那样冲动了
Just doesn't seem to work that way anymore.
我以前是总是急于求成
I used to be in such a hurry all the time, you know?
干什么事都急不可待
Everything was so urgent.
而现在  我觉得
Now, I just, I don't know, I figure...
如果是命中注定  等时机到了自然就会在一起
it's gonna happen, it'll happen when it happens.
我不会离开  她不会离开
I'm not going anywhere, she's not going anywhere.
急什么呢  对吧
What's the rush, right?
罗宾
我不知道那个女生是谁
I have no idea who that girl was.
但她让我走上了正轨
But she set me straight.
自那以后  我只有一个挑战
After that, I had one challenge and one challenge only.
那就是让罗宾・特布罗斯基
Get Robin Scherbatsky
爱上我
to fall in love with me.
挑战成功
Challenge completed.
爱你  一百年永不变 *
* Why would I stop loving you a hundred years from now